Dr Swapnil Mishra

Email: s.mishra@nus.edu.sg
Web: https://smishra.dev/

Research Profile

Dr Swapnil Mishra is an Assistant Professor at Saw Swee Hock School of Public Health at NUS. His research is on spatiotemporal statistics and Bayesian machine learning, applied to public policy, global health and social science. Swapnil won the NUS PYP (2024), the NRF Fellowship (2023), Blackwell-Rosenbluth Award (2022), and the SPI-M-O Award for Modelling and Data Support (2022) for modeling advice provided to the UK government during the COVID-19 pandemic. In 2022, he co-founded the Machine Learning & Global Health network (www.MLGH.net) of researchers spanning three continents with a kickoff workshop held in Kigali, Rwanda at ICLR in 2023.

Education, Academic and Teaching

Education, Academic and Teaching	
<u>Education</u>	
2015 – 2019 Ph	Australian National University – Computational Social Science, Research School of Computer Science
	Thesis title: Linking Models for Collective Attention in Social Media.
2012 – 2014 MS	c Australian National University – Machine Learning, Research School of Computer Science
	Thesis title: Implementation and Experiments with Novel Parallel and Bursty Non-parametric
	Topic Models
2005 – 2009 BEr	University of Pune - Computer Engineering, Department of Computer Engineering
Academic Positions	
2023 - Present	National University of Singapore – Assistant Professor
2023 - Present	IDRTO, National Centre for Infectious Diseases – Visiting Investigator
2021 - 2022	University of Copenhagen – Assistant Professor in Machine Learning and Public Health
2019 - 2021	Imperial College London – Postdoctoral researcher in Geostatistics
2015 - 2019	Australian National University – Research Assistant: Computational Media Lab
2014 - 2015	Data61 (CSIRO) – Research Assistant: Optimisation research Group
2012 - 2014	Australian National University/Data61(NICTA) - Research Assistant: Machine learning research Group
Scholarships, prizes and awards	
2024	Presidential Young Professorship (Class of 2024)
2023	Singapore NRF Fellowship (Class of 2023)
2022	Blackwell-Rosenbluth Award
2022	SPI-M-O Award for Modelling and Data Support
2021	The Queen's Anniversary Prize 2021 – Imperial College COVID-19 Response Team, United Kingdom.
2018	ICWSM Travel Grant
2018	ANU Vice Chancellor Travel Grant
2016	CIKM Travel Grant
2015	Australia International Student PhD scholarship
Grants	
2023	NRF-NRFF15-2023-0010(SGD 3.1 million) (PI)
2023	Start-up Grant, NUS (SGD 250,000) (PI)
2022	Digital Technology Development Award, Wellcome Trust (USD 612,665) (Co-PI)
2020	Imperial COVID-19 Response Fund (£46,975) (Co-PI)
2020 2020	Microsoft AI for Health program (\$130,000) (Co-PI) Amazon AWS Compute Grant (\$45,000) (Co-PI)
Consulting	
2020	New York State: Advisory group for COVID-19 response
2020	Herbert Smith Freehils: Advisory group for COVID-19 response
Selected Invited/Keynote speaker Presentations	
2023	Statistical Methods Talk, Duke-NUS
2022	Seminar on Advances in Probabilistic Machine Learning, Helsinki
2022	Invited Talk: Pandemic forecasting: Lessons learned from COVID-19, IISA, Bengaluru
2022	VinFuture Innova Talk, Hanoi, Vietnam
2020	Keynote lecture: Scalable Mechanistic Bayesian Models for COVID-19 Transmissions, Stan-Con 2020
2020	Invited lecture: Estimating the number of infections and the impact of non-pharmaceutical interventions
	on COVID-19, European Consortium of Mathematics in Industry
2020	Invited lecture: Estimating the number of infections and R(t) for COVID-19 with a Semi-mechanistic
=	Hierarchical Bayesian Model, DeepMind
2019	Invited lecture: VAE to learn functions, RSS 2019, Belfast

Publication Summary

Google Scholar

https://scholar.google.co.uk/citations?user=RqbpaXcAAAAJ&hl=en